American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIf. 1866-1886 APS.Archives.IIf APS.Archives.IIf
American Philosophical Society
American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIf
1866-1886
APS.Archives.IIf
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the American Philosophical Society Archives. For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
American Philosophical Society.
- Papers
  - Letter to J. Peter Lesley, Jan.1, 1866; 8x5; Belcourt, George Antoine, 1803-1874
    Scope and Contents note
    Rustico, Prince Edward Island, A.L.S. 3p.and end. Regarding his French-Ojibway dictionary and plans for its publication. See Pro., X, 203-204.
  - Cards announcing meetings, Jan. 5, 1866 - Jan. 7, 1870; American Philosophical Society
    Printed D. 17 leaves with 4 cards per leaf. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 27, 1866; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Joseph Henry. 1p. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 7, 1866; 13-1/4x8-1/2; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Warington W.Smyth. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall]. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, February 12, 1866; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Jones, William P. (William Patterson)
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.Com.S. Concerning relation of gravitation and magnetism. Read: February 16, 1866. See Pro., X, 204.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 14, 1866; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Brussels, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Quetelet. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte and end. In French. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, February 22, 1866; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Jones, William P. (William Patterson)
    Philadelphia, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.Com.S. Nine points in the theory of terrestrial magnetism.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, March 2, 1866; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Jones, William P. (William Patterson)
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsements. A.Com.S. Supplementary points to the theory of terrestrial magnetism.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, March 7, 1866; 4 1/2" x 7 1/8"; Brickenstein, H. A.
    Secretary of A.P.S., Bethlehem, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Thinks that the United Brethren will approve the publication of certain of the [David] Zeisberger manuscripts. See Pro., X, 207.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, March 8, 1866; 7 7/8'' x 9 7/8''; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Smithsonian Institution, Washington, 3 pp. and endorsement. L.S. Presentation and withdrawal of Father [George A.] Belcourt's memoir from the Smithsonian. Smithsonian building damaged by fire. $150,000-$200,000 repairs necessary. Possible combination of the Smithsonian library with libraries of Capitol and of Congress. The same to be opened to the public. FILM 235 FRAME27
  - Letter to [J. Peter] Leslie, March 27, 1866; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Agassiz, Alexander, 1835-1910
    [sic], Museum of Comparative Zoology, Cambridge, Mass., 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Wishes to exchange a few copies of his father's contributions for an equivalent part of A.P.S. Transactions. See Pro., X, 209.
  - Letter to [J. Peter Lesley], April 25, 1866; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Taliaferro, E.
    College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, va., 2pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Wishes to know whether any "encouragement" may be held out by the A.P.S. for the publication of a "treatise on
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Philadelphia, April 26, 1866; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Kaiserlich-Königliche Geographische Gesellschaft (Austria)
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Franz Hauery. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte] and end. In German. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - The laws of the French Language." Read:, May 4, 1866; Taliaferro, E. 4-25-1866
    See Pro., X, 242. Not found May 2011.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 5, 1866; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Joseph Henry. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte]. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Report of the special committee on T. E. Blackwell's memoir, May 6, 1866; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    "Hydrology of the St. Lawrence," Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: John C. Trautwine, T. P[eter] Lesley. Publication of first part of memoir in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to Joseph Henry, May 8, 1866; 5" x 8"; Greer, James
    Dayton, Ohio, 12 pp. and endorsement. A.Com.S. Regarding the discovery of the three fossil fish in the sand bluffs of Mississippi near Vicksburg. See minutes, June 15, 1866, in Pro., X, 256.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, May 10, 1866; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Belcourt, George Antoine, 1803-1874
    Rustico, Prince Edward Island, A.L.S. 4p. In French. Enc. Concerning his French-Ojibway dictionary. Cf. Pro., X, 1256. For enc.,see: Belcourt. French-Ojibway dictionary; May 1866.
  - Minutes of stated meeting of... Philadelphia, May 11, 1866; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; American Philosophical Society. Board of officers
    1 p. and endorsement. Moved that a trust fund be established for the erection of a fireproof building for the Society.
  - Report of the committee of... upon paper signed "Prometheus" offered for the Magellanic premium, May 11, 1866; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; American Philosophical Society. Board of officers
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. Do not recommend invention of "Prometheus" for Magellanic award.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, May 31, 1866; 5" x 8"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Smithsonian Institution, [Washington], 2 pp. A.L.S. Encloses communication from James Greer, dated Dayton, May 8, 1866, (q.v.). Requests suggestions as to an answer. FILM 235 FRAME 28
  - French-Ojibway dictionary, May, 1866; 13x8-1/4, 15x9-1/2; Belcourt, George Antoine, 1803-1874
    A.D. 12p. In French. Consists of a preface to the dictionary and a specimen page (A to Abonner). Enclosed originally in Belcourt to Lesley; May 10, 1866.
  - Letter to [J. Peter] Leslie [sic], June 12, 1866; 7 5/8" x 9 3/4"; Köhler, William
    Austinville, Va., 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding lead ores found near Austinville. The letter has been corrected for the press. See Pro., X, 270.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 21, 1866; 9x7-1/4; Royal Geological Society of Ireland
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Robert H. Scott and Robert Runes. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte] and end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 22, 1866; 10-3/4x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Joseph Henry. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Report of committee on the inadvisability of publishing 0. Reichenbach's paper on geology, July 10, 1866; 9-3/4x7-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: F.V. Hayden. 1p. Mutilated. Cf. Minutes, May 18, 1866.
  - Letter to John C. Cresson, July 10, 1866; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Horsford, Eben Norton, 1818-1893
    Cambridge, [Mass.], 2pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning a brilliant rainbow seen on July 8. Printed in Pro., X, 258.
  - Report of committee in favor of publication of the Ojibway dictionary by Belcourt, July 14, 1866; 9-3/4x7-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: F.V.Hayden, J.P.Lesley and P.E. Chase. 1p. See Pro., X, 259.
  - Letter to John C. Cresson, July 24, 1866; 5" x 8"; Moore, M.
    Trenton Falls, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning the identity of "a small copper coin of the weight of forty two grains." Printed in part in Pro., X, 270.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 27, 1866; 10x8; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Richd. Kippis. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[ednall] and end. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 27, 1866; 10-1/4x8
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.H.Miller. 1p.and end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Sept. 20, 1866; 7-1/2x5; Duane, William, 1807-1882
    A.L.S. 1p.,end.by J.P.L[esley]. Presents Peter Legaux's meteorological records.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 28, 1866; 10x8-1/2; Gesellschaft zur Beförderung der Gesammten Naturwissenschaften zu Marburg
    Marburg, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Heusinger. 1p.,end.by J.L.LeC[onte], and end. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, October 7, 1866; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Greer, James
    Secretary of A.P.S., Dayton, Ohio, 3 pp. A.L.S. Regarding natural coke pit near Richmond, Va. Encloses extracts from Sir Charles Lyell's pamphlet on the coal fields of America, for publication.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, October 7, 1866; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Peale, Franklin, 1795-1870
    Secretary of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Will prepare an obituary notice of the late Mr. Matthias W. Baldwin. See Pro., X, 273.
  - Letter to Peter Lesley, Philadelphia, Oct., 1866; 8x5; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.)
    Washington, A.L.S.: J.E. Hilgard. 1p.,end.,and end. Forwards publication. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to the Natural academy of sciences, Nov. 3, 1866; 5-1/4x7-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: J.P.Lesley. 1p.,end. Copy. "To Dr. Wolcott Gibbs..." Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, November 12, 1866; 5" x 7 3/4"; Reed, William B. (William Bradford), 1806-1876
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. Resignation from membership in A.P.S. See Pro., X, 276.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, November 13, 1866; 7" x 10"; Eddy, Richard, 1828-1906
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. The librarian of the Historical Society of Pennsylvania asks permission to copy and publish the letters of Penn and Logan, as copied by the late Mrs. Deborah Logan. Read: November 16, 1866.
  - Letter to George Bacon Wood, November 17, 1866; Fraley, F., (Frederick), 1804-1901
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s P. James, W[est] Haverford, December 16, 1866; 5" x 8 1/8"; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    2pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Will leave another wood cut at A.P.S. rooms tomorrow. Encloses bill from artist, Mr. Edward Sheppard, for $60.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., December 19, 1866; 4 7/8" x 7 7/8"; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Essex Institute, Salem, [Mass.], 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Encloses prospectus of a new natural history magazine (American Naturalist). Requests cooperation of the A.P.S. See Pro., X, 330.
  - Remarks upon sudden fall of temperature accompanied by a rise of the barometer., December 21, 1866; 4 15/16" x 8"; Cresson, John C. (John Chapman), 1806-1876
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. Com. See minutes, December 21, 1866, in Pro., X, 296.
  - Letter to George Bacon Wood, December 26, 1866; Jenks, Harriet N.
  - Letter to ----, January 14, 1867; 5" x 6 1/2"; Jenks, Harriet N.
    Boston, 1 p. A.L.S. Encloses date of her father's death, together with obituary (missing) by the Rev. George w. Blagden. [Rev. William Jenks, d. November 13, 1866.]
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 18, 1867; 13x8; Great Britain. War Office
    Southampton, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Henry James. 1p.,end. by E.O.K[endall], and end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, February 27, 1867; 5" x 8"; Greer, James
    Dayton, Ohio, 3 pp. A.L.S. Concerning publication of his communication to the Smithsonian Institution regarding three fossil fish, in A.P.S. Proceedings.
  - Letter to ----, March 6, 1867; 5" x 8"; Loomis, Elias, 1811-1889
    Yale College, [New Haven], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Orders A.P.S. Transactions, II, III, and IV. "as complete as they can be made."
  - Letter to J. Otis Kendall, March 18, 1867; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Hagedane, C. F.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Has forwarded APS publications to Germany.
  - Letter to the President of A.P.S., April 29, 1867; 7 3/4" X 9 5/8"; Merrick, J. Vaughan
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. L.S. Resolution adopted at meeting of members of several societies regarding erection of building on Penn Square.
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s P. James, May 14, 1867; 5 1/8" x 8 1/8"; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    W[est] Haverford, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Wishes to pay half of the bill for corrections made in his paper, but regards the other half as due to "office errors" for which he is not liable.
  - Letter to Ed[ward] D. Cope, May 17, 1867; 5" x 8"; James, Thomas Potts, 1803-1882
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. Dr.L.S. Refusal to reduce bill for extra printing charges.
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s P. James, W[est] Haverford, May 27, 1867; 5 1/8" x 8 1/8"; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Thinks that the committee of the A.P.S. should "look to the printer" for reimbursement of extra charges due to compositors' errors.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, June 1, 1867; 4 7/8" x 7 7/8"; Sheafer, P. W. (Peter Wenrick), b. 1819
    Pottsville, Pa., 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests "copy of terms of reward offered for utilising the fine Coal dirt gathered about our Anthracite Colliers."
  - Letter to [the American Philosophical Society], August or September, 1867; 8 1/4" x 10 5/8"; Dick, A., and Cie
    Paris, n.d., but ca. 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. Inquires whether A.P.S. would care to purchase any of Prof. Richter's new metal, indium, A. Dick & Co. being the agents of the Royal Saxon factories. Read: Sept. 20, 1867. Pro., X, 343.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Oct. 8, 1867; 7-1/2x5; Hinrichs, Gustavus Detlef, 1836-1923
    Iowa City, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Donates volume.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., October 10, 1867; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hayden, F. V. (Ferdinand Vandeveer), 1829-1887
    Julesburg, Colo., 3 pp. and endorsement. A.Com.S. Observations upon the Indian history of the Colorado region. Regarding the use of stone arrow points by the Pawnees in very early times. Printed in full, under date of, in Proceedings, X, 352-353.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, October 12, 1867; Cleveland, Charles Dexter, 1802-1869
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Philadelphia, Oct. 19, 1867; 8x5; Jarvis, Edward, 1803-1884
    Dorchester, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s P. James, November 7, 1867; 5" x 8"; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, 1p. and endorsement. A.L.S. offers to pay cost of corrections (half of Sherman & Co's. bill) to publication committee of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Nov. 11, 1867; 10x8; Hinrichs, Gustavus Detlef, 1836-1923
    Iowa City, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Asks for notice that his book was received.
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s P. James, November 18, 1867; 5" x 8"; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires whether the publication committee of the A.P.S. will be interested in his supplement to Leidy's "Extinct Reptiles of the Cretaceous formation in the United States."
  - Letter to [Edward D.] Cope, December 6, 1867; 5" x 7 3/4"; James, Thomas Potts, 1803-1882
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. Dr. L.S. Thinks Prof. Cope's new article will be accepted for the A.P.S. Transactions. Publication committee agrees to accept Cope's terms as to payment of printer.
  - Letter to T[homas] P. James, December 8, 1867; 5" x 8"; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses $15 for corrections made in his paper.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., December, 1867; 5" x 8 1/8"; Barnard, Henry, 1811-1900
    Washington, n.d., but ca. 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Asks for a brief history of the A.P.S. for a report upon schools of agriculture and mechanic arts. Endorsed as read: December 20, 1867.
  - Letter to the American Philosop[hica]l So[ciety], 1867; 4 5/8" x 8 3/8"; Philadelphia. Board of revision of taxes
    Philadelphia, ----, 1 p. Pr.D. Notice of assessment of A.P.S. property at $30,000 for the year 1868.
  - Circular, at a meeting of the aid committee..., 1867?; American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the President [of the American philosophical society], Jan. 17, 1868; 8x5-1/2; Dionisotti, Carlo, 1824-1899
    Turin, A.L.S. 1p.and end. In French. Donates publication.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Jan. 17, 1868; 7x5; Stockwell, John N. (John Nelson), 1832-1920
    Brecksville, Ohio, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Donates publication.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] B. Wood and Cha[rle]s B. Trego, February 27, 1868; 5" x 8"; O'Neill, Charles, 1821-1893
    House of Representatives, Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Has received A.P.S. resolution asking that Congress may order an early examination of the coast of Alaska, and will present the same to the House.
  - Letter to J.P[eter] Lesley, Philadelphia, March 28, 1868; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Academia Real das Sciencias de Lisboa
    Lisbon, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.M.Latino Coelh. 1p. In French. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to ----, June 8, 1868; 5" x 8"; James, Thomas Potts, 1803-1882
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. [Elias] Durand "declines the appointment of agent for the Am. Philos. Society for securing the Mirchaux legacy."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 25, 1868; 12x9-1/4; Magyar Tudományos Akadémia
    Budapest, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Arany. 1p. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Edward D. Cope, July 28, 1868; 7 3/4" x 10"; Trego, Charles B., 1794-1874
    L-12 Philadelphia, 1 p. Dr.L.I. Concerning prospective publication of Dr. Cope's paper.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, August 19, 1868; 8" x 12 1/2"; Edwards, Howard, 1833-1925?
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. A.L.S. Requests loan of map of the "Indian Walk," in order to make a copy thereof.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 1, 1868; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Kongelige Nordiske oldskriftselskab (Denmark)
    Copenhagen, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Engelhardt. 1p.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 17, 1868; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Brussels, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Quetelet. 1p., In French. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, Oct. 2, 1868; 8x5; Robinson, Moncure, 1802-1891
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Forwards Michel Chevalier's donation.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 16, 1868; 10x8-1/4; Physikalische Gesellschaft zu Berlin
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: G.Quincke. 1p. In German. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Oct. 22, 1868; 4x7; Kirchhoff, G. (Gustav), 1824-1887
    Heidelburg, A.L.S. 1p. In German. Through the Smithsonian institution he has received the Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 1, 1868; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Société de physique et d'histoire naturelle de Genève
    Geneva, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Marignac. 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for Proceedings and forwards publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 5, 1868; 9x5-1/2; K.K. Sternwarte zu Prag
    A.L.S.: K.Hornstein. 1p. In German. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 11, 1868; 10x8; Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Henry E. Roscoe and Josh. Baxendell. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 14, 1868; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Schrätter. 1p. In German. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to [Edward D.] Cope, December 15, 1868; 5" x 7 15/16"; James, Thomas Potts, 1803-1882
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. Dr.L.S. Requests Prof. Cope to submit plates intended to go with his article, in order that correct estimate of cost of publication may be obtained.
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s P. James, R[oo]ms A.P.S., December 16, 1868; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Reasons for the withdrawal of certain plates from article on fossil reptiles.
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s P. James, December 30, 1868; 5 3/8" x 8 1/8"; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. Hopes that his paper will not be sent to press before all or most of the wood cuts are finished.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 7, 1869; 10x8; Royal Society of Edinburgh
    Edinburgh, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.H.Balfour. 1p. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 9, 1869; 10-3/4x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Joseph Henry. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, January 12, 1869; 7 5/8" x 9 5/8"; Coupeé, Henry
    Lehigh University, South Bethlehem, Pa., 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Requests loan of Mariana's History of Spain for six months. Granted, February 12, 1869.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 12, 1869; 9-3/4x8; Natural History Society of Northumberland, Durham, & Newcastle-upon-Tyne
    Newcastle, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Henry Bowman Brady and George Hodge. 1p. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Ed[ward] D. Cope, January 25, 1869; 7 5/8" x 12 1/2"; James, Thomas Potts, 1803-1882
    Philadelphia, 1 p. Dr.L.S. Concerning difficulties regarding wood cuts and lithographs for Dr. Cope's paper, executed by John Collins.
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s P. James, January 29, 1869; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.L.S. Appointment to meet committee "on 3rd day at 11.30 A.M."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan., 1869; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Akademie der Wissenschaften in Göttingen
    Göttingen, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wöhler. 1p.,end. In German. Thanks for Proceedings and forwards publication.
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s P. James, February 9, 1869; 4 7/8" x 7 3/8"; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia,1P. A.L.S. Regrets illness of Mr. James. Cannot meet committee before sixth or seventh day. "[John] Collins comes on slowly with the plates.. ."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 12, 1869; 9-3/4x8; Society of Antiquaries of Scotland
    Edinburgh, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.T.McCulloch. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, February 20, 1869; 4 7/8" x 7 1/2"; Bridges, Robert, 1806-1882
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Regrets that he is too busy to prepare an obituary notice of Mr. [John] cassin.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb., 1869; 10x8; Kaiserlich-Königliche Zoologisch-Botanische Gesellschaft in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Georg R.v. Frauenfeld. 1p. In German. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, [Feb?], 1869; 10x8; Royal Society of Edinburgh
    Edinburgh, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J. H. Balfour. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 3, 1869; 10-1/2x8; Russia. Observatoire physique central
    St. Petersburg, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: H.C.Wild. 1p. In French. Thanks for Proceedings.